Hensley mss., 1952-1981 LMC 1482
Lilly Library
Hensley mss.
1952-1981
Lilly Library
Hensley, Joe 1926-2007
LMC 1482
3 Boxes
1 folio
The Hensley mss, 1952-1981, consists of the correspondence, writings, and other related materials of Joseph Louis "Joe L." Hensley, 1926-2007, science fiction author and Indiana 5th circuit court judge.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
Joe L. Hensley, 1926-2007, was an author and 5th Circuit Court judge of Indiana, known for his many science fiction and mystery novels. Born and raised in Bloomington, Indiana, he got his B.A. in 1950 and his L.L.B. from Indiana University in 1955. He was well-known in the sci-fi fandom and received the First Fandom Hall of Fame Award in 2006. Manuscripts present in this collection include: Black Roads (Laser Books, 1976), A Killing in Gold (Doubleday, 1978), Legislative Body (Doubleday, 1972), The Poison Summer (Doubleday, 1974), Rivertown Risk (Doubleday, 1977), A Song of Corpus Juris (Doubleday, 1974), Minor Murders (Doubleday, 1979), and Outcasts (Doubleday, 1981).
Arrangement
The mss. is arranged into the following series: I. Correspondence, II. Writings, III. Printed Materials, and IV. Miscellaneous.
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence contains letters to Hensley from 1952-1981. Writings includes the drafts, printer's manuscripts, and galleys of Hensley's major novels and short stories. Printed Materials includes various periodicals and chapbooks collected by Hensley. Miscellaneous includes clippings about Hensley's career and two photographs.
Acquisition Information
Purchase: 1981
American Literature--Indiana; Science fiction; Detective and mystery stories; Lawyers --Indiana.; Hensley, Joe 1926-2007
- I. Correspondence
  - 1952-1953 (Box 1)
  - 1954-1955 (Box 1)
  - 1957-1960 (Box 1)
  - 1961-1963 (Box 1)
  - 1964-1966 (Box 1)
  - 1967-1968 (Box 1)
  - 1969 (Box 1)
  - 1970 (Box 1)
  - 1971 (Box 1)
  - 1972 (Box 1)
  - 1973 Jan-Aug (Box 1)
  - 1973 Sept-Dec (Box 1)
  - 1974 Jan-Apr (Box 1)
  - 1974 May-Sept (Box 1)
  - 1974 Oct-Dec (Box 1)
  - 1975 Jan-Feb (Box 1)
  - 1975 Mar-Apr (Box 1)
  - 1975 May-June (Box 1)
  - 1975 July-Aug (Box 1)
  - 1975 Sept-Dec (Box 1)
  - 1976 Jan-Mar (Box 1)
  - 1976 Apr-Dec (Box 1)
  - 1977 Jan-Aug (Box 1)
  - 1977 Sept-Dec (Box 1)
  - 1978 Jan-Apr (Box 1)
  - 1978 May-Aug (Box 1)
  - 1978 Sept-Dec (Box 1)
  - 1979 Jan-May (Box 1)
  - 1979 June-Sept (Box 1)
  - 1979 Oct-Dec (Box 1)
  - 1980 Jan-Feb (Box 1)
  - 1980 Mar-May (Box 1)
  - 1980 June-Aug (Box 1)
  - 1980 Sept-Dec (Box 1)
  - 1981 Jan-Feb (Box 1)
  - 1981 Mar-May (Box 1)
  - 1981 June-Aug (Box 1)
  - N.D. (Box 1)
  - Rejection slips (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
- II. Writings
  - Black Roads version 1 (1/2) (Box 1)
  - Black Roads version 1 (2/2) (Box 1)
  - Black Roads version 2 (1/2) (Box 1)
  - Black Roads version 2 (2/2) (Box 2)
  - "Borderlands" (Box 2)
  - "Dark Edge" (Box 2)
  - "The Deeps" (Box 2)
  - "A Girl in Aces" (Box 2)
  - A Killing in Gold (1/2) (Box 2)
  - A Killing in Gold (2/2) (Box 2)
  - Legislative Body draft (1/2) (Box 2)
  - Legislative Body draft (2/2) (Box 2)
  - Legislative Body printer's ms (1/3) (Box 2)
  - Legislative Body printer's ms (2/3) (Box 2)
  - Legislative Body printer's ms (3/3) (Box 2)
  - Minor Murders draft (Box 2)
  - Minor Murders printer's ms (1/3) (Box 2)
  - Minor Murders printer's ms (2/3) (Box 2)
  - Minor Murders printer's ms (3/3) (Box 2)
  - Outcasts (1/3) (Box 2)
  - Outcasts (2/3) (Box 2)
  - Outcasts (3/3) (Box 2)
  - Outcasts galley 1 (Box 2)
  - Outcasts galley 2 (Box 2)
  - Outcasts drafts and fragments (Box 2)
  - "Outcry" (Box 2)
  - Poison Summer draft (1/2) (Box 2)
  - Poison Summer draft (2/2) (Box 2)
  - Poison Summer printer's ms (1/2) (Box 2)
  - Poison Summer printer's ms (2/2) (Box 2)
  - "The Red and Green" (Box 2)
  - "Reunion" (Box 2)
  - Rivertown Risk version 1 (1/3) (Box 3)
  - Rivertown Risk version 1 (2/3) (Box 3)
  - Rivertown Risk version 1 (3/3) (Box 3)
  - Rivertown Risk version 2 (Box 3)
  - Rivertown Risk printer's ms (1/3) (Box 3)
  - Rivertown Risk printer's ms (2/3) (Box 3)
  - Rivertown Risk printer's ms (3/3) (Box 3)
  - Rivertown Risk drafts and fragments (Box 3)
  - Song of Corpus Juris version 1 (1/3) (Box 3)
  - Song of Corpus Juris version 1 (2/3) (Box 3)
  - Song of Corpus Juris version 1 (3/3) (Box 3)
  - Song of Corpus Juris version 2 (1/3) (Box 3)
  - Song of Corpus Juris version 2 (2/3) (Box 3)
  - Song of Corpus Juris version 2 (3/3) (Box 3)
  - Song of Corpus Juris printer's ms (1/3) (Box 3)
  - Song of Corpus Juris printer's ms (2/3) (Box 3)
  - Song of Corpus Juris printer's ms (3/3) (Box 3)
  - "Star Way" (Box 3)
  - "The Sun Hunters" (Box 3)
  - "The Widow" (Box 3)
  - Fragments and ideas (Box 3)
- III. Printed Materials
  - Don-O-Saur 39, 1974 Dec (Box 3)
  - The Double: Bill Symposium (Box 3)
  - Indiana Fantasy (Box 3)
  - The Locked Poem 8 (Box 3)
  - Midamericon Progress Report 2, 1936 Sept (Box 3)
  - The Mystery Fancier 2.6, 1978 Nov-Dec (Box 3)
  - Nyarlathotep 6 (Box 3)
  - Pause (Box 3)
  - Peon, 1954 Nov (Box 3)
  - The Poisoned Pen 3.1, 1980 Jan-Feb (Box 3)
  - The Shadow Magazine, 1979 Oct (Box 3)
  - Sirrvish 12 (Box 3)
  - Star Magazine, 1974 Mar 24 (Foliobox 28)
  - Student Lawyer, 1977 Oct (Box 3)
  - Yandro, 1974 Apr (Box 3)
  - Yandro, 1975 June (Box 3)
  - Yandro, 1976 Aug (Box 3)
  - Yandro, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
- IV. Miscellaneous
  - 1962-1975 (Box 3)
  - 1976-1978 (Box 3)
  - 1979-1981 (Box 3)
  - Photographs (Box 3)